<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloudy with a twist on Cloudy Dreams</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloudy with a twist on Cloudy Dreams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 15:48:08 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Distributed Intrusion Detection For Zero-Trust Multi-Access Edge Computing</title>
      <link>/article/prob_cids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 15:48:08 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/prob_cids/</guid>
      <description>This paper was published in IFIP NOMS 2023 and is available here
The abstract of this paper is as follows:
With the advent of Multi-Access Edge Computing (MEC) in 5G, there is a shift in the core processing and deployment of applications to the edge of the network. This enables applications requiring ultra low latency response times and high bandwidth but also exposes them to new cyber attacks. One of the proposed ways to strengthen application security in MEC is to use Zero Trust Strategies (ZTS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Collaborative Architectures For Intrusion Detection In Multi-Access Edge Computing</title>
      <link>/article/hybrid_cids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 15:48:08 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/hybrid_cids/</guid>
      <description>This paper was published in IFIP NOMS 2022 and is available here
The abstract of this paper is as follows:
Multi-Access Edge Computing (MEC) provides high network bandwidth and ultra-low latency response time but also inherits the security vulnerabilities of cloud computing to Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attacks. To guard MEC nodes from such attacks, previous work has proposed the use of Collaborative Intrusion Detection Systems (CIDS) as a prime candidate for attack detection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Collaborative Intrusion Detection System Architectures in Mobile Edge Computing</title>
      <link>/article/mec_cids_evaluation_book_chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 15:48:08 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/mec_cids_evaluation_book_chapter/</guid>
      <description>This book chapter is published in Springer Nature and is available here
The abstract of this book chapter is as follows:
With the advent of 5th Generation (5G) of mobile networks, a diverse range of new computer networking technologies are being devised to meet the stringent demands of applications that require ultra-low latency, high bandwidth and geolocation-based services. Mobile Edge Computing (MEC) is a prominent example of such an emerging technology, which provides cloud computing services at the edge of the network using mobile base stations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Centralised vs Distributed Collaborative Intrusion Detection Systems in Multi-Access Edge Computing</title>
      <link>/article/centralised_vs_distributed_cids_in_mec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:48:08 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/centralised_vs_distributed_cids_in_mec/</guid>
      <description>This paper was published in IFIP Networking 2020 and is available here
The abstract of this paper is as follows:
With the rapid adoption of next generation networking architectures in 5G, like Multi-Access Edge Computing (MEC), there is a shift in the core processing capabilities to the edge of the network. This helps facilitate higher bandwidth and ultra-low latency responses, but can increase the attack surface for cyber-attacks like Denial of Service (DoS) and Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elasticsearch Snapshot Archival for the Brave</title>
      <link>/article/elasticsearch-snapshot-archival-for-the-brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 15:48:08 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/elasticsearch-snapshot-archival-for-the-brave/</guid>
      <description>This article is available in the Deloitte Platform Engineering website here. I wrote this back in 2018 when I was working on an interesting issue we were facing in getting access to Elasticsearch snapshot information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
